<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emily Garcia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emily Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of R and Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/08/the-importance-of-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/08/the-importance-of-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Before I started my computational biology course, I had a very limited experience with coding in general. I got a taste of it when I was enrolled in biostatistics last year, but it never truly occurred me how much the things I learned applied to the world outside of science. 
 And yes, science is wonderful and all, but there’s so much more to statistical analysis than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>0. Introduction 
For project 2, I decided to work with data derived from the popular MOBA (multiplayer online battle arena) League of Legends as developed by Riot. In this video game, players select unique champions to combat other players in team-based matches. I thought it would be fascinating to see the relationships between the many variables that the game has to offer with their diverse cast of playable champions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, eval = TRUE, fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;, warning = F, message = F, tidy=TRUE, tidy.opts=list(width.cutoff=60), R.options=list(max.print=100)) 
0. Introduction 
For this project, I chose to work with two datasets. The first dataset is called netflix and it is composed of 50 days of my Netflix viewing history compiled into three columns: Date, Genre, and Run-time. They were acquired from the Netflix website through their download history function; however, the genres assigned to each of the observations were determined by the genre tags that Netflix auto-assigned them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Emily Garcia Feel free to contact me through:  Email at egarcia9813@gmail.com Github at emadgar  
  Interests  Data analysis Synthetic biology Sociological research  
 Education University of Texas at Austin, Class of 2021  B.S.A. in Biology and a minor in Sociology 
  Skills  Communication and leadership Wet lab bench work Virtual bench work Data analysis Organization and time management</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
